Hello, welcome to the next episode of Learn German in Hindi.
Today we are going to
learn two concepts which are
very important if you are going to learn them at an advanced level, beyond the selfish world,
and this concept is a little more
backward than grammar related, I mean what you have to
learn tomorrow, it is very simple and for that
you will have to put in some hard work,
you will have to use it and
I will also
tell you what I did for that, so let's start, first of all let's
see the concept of time, preposition to work with
progressive, so to understand what this is,
first let's start with our Indian
language, so let me give you a simple example
that I love Anita,
this is I Amit love Anita,
now if I say yours, my Madan, for Marathi, then
what does it mean in Marathi, I love Anita, I
mean in Marathi, I love Anita,
now
Marathi and Hindi, so the meanings are a little more
latest, that is, their mother tongue and
Sanskrit, still you love Hindi, you
love Marathi, so
which one, which one  There is nothing wrong like that, they are
two different languages, their way of speaking
is similar, if you look at English then
you say wait for, not was, so
now have you ever thought that I wait for, till you for,
where does it come from, slight wait and Manita,
why not, that work, we remember
in English Bijnor is very logical Kishanpol,
we remember that brother IS valid for,
okay now in food also it is like this that it is
their preposition with some years, so in
German it is inverter and Anil is
master, finally here in my class some
people ask me that
why don't you understand that you have already learnt English, that is why
you are asking like this, the one who has
help or German will ask the opposite that
I wait and why not, like
in Hindi I love Anita,
why is it there, in Marathi I love Anita,
why is there no answer to that, similarly
in English there is wait for, in German it is water
out, so you have to remember this, every
language has its own meaning, it seems
and till the last few days pain goes away quickly that that
you  When you are new, if
someone is talking to you in Hindi that
I love Anita, then you will understand,
but when you are at an advanced level and this
expectation is that you love Anita, that is why take a
little care of the inches, so right now
which countries are these, that I have
given a list, that I say something that brother
you this time - I mean I am waiting for
you and in effective work, remember, so
this interest is like love's
loyalty, it comes in English, interested in,
understand, in English it depends on something,
in German it is now a little similar,
sometimes it is a little similar
that I can tweet in English without
it, that information is also available in German,
but we will
not rely on that, we will keep learning our own
time, then what is the problem,
secondly, why cancer, I understood that, you have to
remember this, so when you open the locker, then
send whatever you want to do, today
Jai Hanuman, knowledge in these were Prabhu, I do not remember what happens,
then one by one  When the
time comes to use it, you make mistakes, so
for that, I will
tell you my tip, what should I do,
never keep them all together, it will not work, you will
remember it for a short while, you will
pass your exam with it, but it will
not be useful in the long term, first of all, set
one or two new coins in a week
and use them in sentences, I will
remember them like that, baby, remember me tomorrow that the
interest will be immediately, friend, because this
interesting Ramesh has 2 inches in this sentence
for deposit, then I remember, if the
interest is clear here then it will come, but
here in this model of the Android, I am waiting for your answer, then
I immediately remember that the more you
remember your sentences, the easier it will be for you, in
which I said that I have given a list of some of them in the
deep itself and a little description,
you can remember them,
keep them together after dividing them, do not fill it, it is not going to help me,
and the most important thing is
that the time is direct transmission  No, don't
forget that in English we think and use its
light condition, don't do this, this will make mistakes, conduct,
understand, if you have understood all this then the
next concept is a little
related to the situation but is very interesting, that is no
man work front dungar, what does it mean by the name,
if you see we are adding naan and square, then
what happens in it, sometimes
how much is it, square is together,
sometimes no, its meaning is food,
so for this we will use our Hindi concept, to
learn this there is an
idiom for resting, everyone knows
what they say, an idiom in Hindi, to
open, my eyes were opened, what does it
mean that till yesterday I was
walking with my eyes closed, did not I understand
my mistake, I understand something, so
look here eyes
is a word, that papa eye khunga * open
famous are together, so it has another meaning,
then breaking of the waist, breaking of the waist means
not your own actually back, it is breaking
that it is my  I have full courage,
so these are called idioms, the words
of the word excel idioms have
their own different meanings, but when
interesting words come together, a new meaning is
formed, so now see again what you have to
remember in this is that you should not make up your own new idioms,
now what happens is someone has
my own mother tincture, I said it is Marathi,
sometimes what happens is that some existing words which are
in mother Marathi and are similar to Hindi, then
sometimes it goes for transfer, that is, someone who has to
play in Hindi, there is Bollywood in Marathi too,
and if I remember the officer here that
in our Marathi, if we get angry at someone, then we
say teeth on that, that is
dana in Marathi, its
meaning does not come across in Hindi, then it will sound
comedy, red, so that is why always remember
that your mother tongue is not your mother tongue, remember what they have
created, your Hindi or
even English people, do
not do literal translation, if you understand from tomorrow then let's
look at a few of their idioms here, if you
can relate the meaning to some of them, you
can select some new ones like this, I will tell you
I mean the same mirror Bairasia Road is difficult
or add the line sticker oil now means
chem to clear important role ego
plays a very big role like this and then the
second opportunity is successful stay means mode want to
B and vitamin there is no doubt
that this happens or front so and
you are running it
means taking responsibility for something, taking
responsibility for something that
there this my Singh I am responsible for this
or that
Bigg Boss turned around in the most
prominent means paying the price for something
we say in Hindi also that interest
morning you will have to pay the price for this dry ginger
and 10,000 German cold now cancer this is
just press so what you will have to do is you will have to
remember it and as you must have
seen in Hindi also that asafoetida
I just asked you to
tell you the press in English then it will take you time but
forget that if you are not in school if you are at
home then this Remedy Norton School
tell you the idioms in Hindi then it will take you
time because most of those are
used in A Good Night, that is what you  You will say that is why this is the
thing that the words that will come to people with the use
and there can be so many of them in any language
that people get scared because and if you
look at the manager book, there are so many in it, even if you
look at the family, you will say, is it Ritesh, so don't worry,
you don't need to use it in your mouth, you need to know that word to
express yourself at that level,
and then how are you remembering it, again the
same trick is that Baba, you have to do only one
word in a week, one or two in a week,
and as I said, Ravana Dahan, just
remember the phrase, remember its use in a sentence,
I will tell you some viewers, then
you will know how to do it in a very simple way, okay, so first of all,
Baba, come and
install it, I mean,
keep the watch on something, this is my opinion, so on straw day
stunt dance motors, you have to special case that
Baba, mother tongue is very important or
you can subscribe, I mean, there is
no second opinion in it, I mean, there is no
point in it, so
what will be the time to discuss it, dance on estate officers point
During this Fakir One is easy, did
you understand this or else different intestines and you
courtyard means that he should
just take responsibility for something, that is, either
I should keep in mind that there is Sandhi Khairan in the wear,
so now you then there, then solution
technology means that we will have to take
responsibility for whatever we have ourselves and
then enroll appeal means that remote
properties, paint and drawing rooms are
available that my mother tongue
plays a big role in my life, if
you use it like this then we will tell you that
whenever you are
writing your opinion or talking to someone
and you have to take it in the direction, yes this time is relative, it is a
day or a news date, then do
not use it directly, like
I have given a few more in this description,
now you will get a lot of internet money, do
not try to learn everything, keep learning as much as you
can read, as
you go ahead you will keep learning new things
and the more you use it, the more direct it
means update it in your sentence  I will be
able to do it. Today we discussed two concepts, first which
was the wish of squared preposition, water come and
second, you have seen that there will be no man or front,
meaning what is that opportunity or first, so what are
these two options, yesterday Saif
came out, it is simple, we saw that it is the same as it was in Hindi, that
I love Anita
and then that she is with my eyes open,
we have seen this in Hindi in English,
what is important is that she is outside, how many
such practices do you do, I would
say that twice a week, not even two days, you will do one
work with preposition and
one Someshwar problem, in three to four
weeks you will start having these,
I hope you have
understood it completely, we will meet
in the next episode, Nehru